- Captain.
- Yes, sir?
Tell them we wish
to board at once.
- [Machinery Beeping]
- With all due respect,
the ambassadors for the supreme
chancellor wish to board immediately.
Yes, of course.
As you know, our blockade
is perfectly legal,
and we'd be happy
to receive the ambassadors.
I'm TC-14
at your service.
This way, please.
We are greatly honored
by your visit, Ambassadors.
Make yourselves
comfortable.
My master will be
with you shortly.
I have a bad feeling
about this.
- I don't sense anything.
- It's not about the mission, Master.
It's something...
elsewhere, elusive.
Don't center on
your anxieties, Obi-Wan.
Keep your concentration
here and now, where it belongs.
But Master Yoda said
I should be mindful of the future.
But not at the expense
of the moment.
Be mindful of the living Force,
young Padawan.
Yes, Master.
How do you think this trade viceroy
will deal with the chancellor's demands?
These Federation types
are cowards.
The negotiations
will be short.
What?
What did you say?
The ambassadors are Jedi knights,
I believe.
I knew it.
They're here
to force a settlement.
Distract them.
I will contact Lord Sidious.
Are you brain-dead?
I'm not going in there
with two Jedi.
Send a droid.
Is it in their nature
to make us wait this long?
No. I sense an unusual amount of fear
for something as trivial
as this trade dispute.
What is it?
This scheme of yours
has failed, Lord Sidious.
The blockade is finished.
We dare not go against these Jedi.
Viceroy, I don't want
this stunted slime in my sight again.
This turn of events
is unfortunate.
We must accelerate our plans.
Begin landing your troops.
My lord,
is that legal?
I will make it legal.
And the Jedi?
The chancellor should never have brought
them into this. Kill them immediately.
Yes. Yes, my lord.
Uh, as you wish.
Captain, look!
Shields up!
Sorry.
Dioxis.
They must be dead by now.
Destroy what's left of them.
Oh! Excuse me.
- Check it out, Corporal.
We'll cover you.
- Roger, roger.
Uh-oh. Blast them.
What is going on
down there?
We lost the transmission,
sir.
Have you ever encountered
a Jedi knight before, sir?
Well, no, but I don't...
Seal off the bridge.
- Yes, sir.
- That won't be enough, sir.
I want droidekas
up here at once!
We will not
survive this.
[Whining]
Close the blast doors!
That will hold them.
They are still
coming through.
This is impossible!
Where are
those droidekas?
Master! Destroyers!
They have shield
generators!
It's a standoff.
Let's go.
They're no match
for droidekas.
Sir! They've gone up
the ventilation shaft.
- Battle droids.
- It's an invasion army.
This is an odd play
for the Trade Federation.
We've got to warn the Naboo
and contact Chancellor Valorum.
Let's split up. Stow aboard separate
ships and meet down on the planet.
You were right
about one thing, Master.
The negotiations
were short.
Sir, a transmission
from the planet.
It's Queen Amidala herself.
At last we are
getting results.
Again you come before us,
Your Highness.
You will not be so pleased when you hear
what I have to say, Viceroy.
Your trade boycott
of our planet has ended.
I was not aware
of such failure.
I have word that the chancellor's
ambassadors are with you now...
and that you have been commanded
to reach settlement.
I know nothing
of any ambassadors.
You must be mistaken.
Beware, Viceroy.
The Federation
has gone too far this time.
We would never do anything
without the approval of the senate.
You assume too much.
We will see.
- She's right. The senate will never...
- It's too late now.
- Do you think she suspects an attack?
- I don't know.
But we must move quickly to disrupt
all communications down there.
Negotiations haven't started
because the ambassadors aren't there?
How could that be true?
I have assurances from the chancellor
his ambassadors did arrive.
[Distorted Voice] It must...
handiwork... negotiate... ambassadors...
- Nobody would...
- Senator Palpatine.
What's happening?
Check the transmission
generator.
A communications disruption
can mean only one thing: invasion.
The Federation would not
dare go that far.
The senate would revoke their
trade franchise, and they'd be finished.
We must continue to rely
on negotiation.
Negotiation?
We've lost all communications.
And where are
the chancellor's ambassadors?
This is a dangerous situation,
Your Highness.
Our security volunteers
will be no match against
a battle-hardened Federation army.
I will not condone a course of action
that will lead us to war.
- Yes, Viceroy?
- Captain, we've searched the ship,
and there is no trace
of the Jedi.
They may have gotten on
one of your landing craft.
If they're down here, sir,
we'll find them.
Use caution.
These Jedi are not to be underestimated.
[Howling]
[Creatures Snorting, Squawking]
- Oh, no!
- Get away! Get out of here!
- Get down!
- [Whimpering]
Ay-yee-yee! Wha!
Was'n dat?
Hey, wait!
Oh, mooie-mooie!
I love you!
You almost got us killed.
Are you brainless?
- I spake.
- The ability to speak does
not make you intelligent.
- Now, get out of here.
- No, no, mesa stay.
Mesa culled JarJar Binks.
Mesa your humble servant.
- That won't be necessary.
- Oh, but it 'tis.
'Tis demanded
by the gods, it 'tis.
- Oh, no! Whoo!
- Stay down!
You saved my again.
- What's this?
- A local.
- Let's get out of here
before more droids show up.
- More?
" More" did you spake?
Ex-squeeze-me, but de mostest
safest place would be Gunga City.
Is where I grew up.
'Tis a hidden city.
- A city?
- Uh-huh.
- Can you take us there?
- Uh, on second thought, no.
- Not really, no.
- No?
'Tis embarrassing,
but, uh, my afraid
my've been banished.
My forgotten.
Da bosses would do terrible tings to me.
- Terrible tings to me
if me goen back dare.
-[Rumbling Sound]
- You hear that?
- Yah.
That is the sound of a thousand
terrible things heading this way.
If they find us,
they will crush us,
grind us into tiny pieces
and blast us into oblivion.
Oh. Yousa point
is well seen.
This way. Hurry!
[Creatures Chittering, Hooting]
- How much further?
- Wesa goen underwater, okeyday?
Ah, my warning you.
Gungans no liken outsiders,
so don't spect a warm welcome.
Oh, don't worry. This hasn't
been our day for warm welcomes.
Ar, ar, ar!
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh!
Yousa follow me now,
okeyday?
[JarJar]
So good bein home!
[Gasping, Chattering]
- Oh, me gusa.
- Hata-hata.
[Chattering Continues]
- [Creature Growling]
- Hey, yousa.
- Stopa dare!
- Heyo-dales, Cap'n Tarpals.
Mesa back!
Noah gain, JarJar.
Yousa goen tada bosses.
Yousa in big dudu
dis time.
Ohh.
Ay, ay.
[Gasps]
How wude.
[Grunts]
Tkk-tkk-tkk-tkk-tkk-tkk-tkk!
Yousa cannot bees hair.
Dis army of Mackineeks
up dare is new weesong.
A droid army is about to attack
the Naboo. We must warn them.
Wesa no like da Naboo.
Tkk-tkk-tkk-tkk-tkk.
Da Naboo tink
day so smarty.
Day tink
day brains so big.
Once those droids take control of the
surface, they will take control of you.
Mesa no tink so.
Day not know of uss-en.
You and the Naboo form
a symbiont circle.
What happens to one of you will affect
the other. You must understand this.
Wesa no carrrre-nn
about da Naboo.
Then speed us on our way.
Wesa ganna
speed yous away.
We could use a transport.
Wesa give yousa
una bongo.
- Hmm?
- Da speediest way tooda Naboo...
'tis goen through
the planet core.
Now...
go.
Thank you for your help.
We leave in peace.
Master, what's a bongo?
A transport, I hope.
Deysa setten
yousa up.
Goen through da planet core?
Bad bombin'.
Mmm... any help here
would be hot.
Master,
we're short on time.
We'll need a navigator
to get us through the planet's core.
This Gungan
may be of help.
What is to become
ofJarJar Binks here?
Hisen soon to be
pune-ished.
- Ohh.
- I saved his life.
He owes me what you call
a " life-debt."
Your gods demand that his life
belongs to me now.
Binkssssss,
yousa havena liveplay
with thisen hisen?
Mm, uh-huh.
[Loud Blubbering]
Begone wit him!
Count me outta
dis one.
Better dead here
than dead in da core.
Yee gods!
What mesa sayin?
[Engine Humming]
Dis is nutsen.
Oh, gooberfish!
- Why were you banished, JarJar?
- It's a longo tale-o,
buta small part of it
would be mesa... clumsy.
- You were banished
because you were clumsy?
- Yousa might'n be sayin dat.
Mesa caused mabbe one,
two-y lettle bitty axadentes, huh?
Yud-say
boom da gassar,
den crashin der boss's heyblibber,
den banished.
- Wuh-oh!
- [Growling]
Big gooberfish!
Huge-o teeth!
[Roaring]
- There's always a bigger fish.
- Mesa tink we goen back now.
[Roaring]
[Engines Howling]
The invasion is on schedule,
my lord.
I have the senate bogged down
in procedures.
They will have no choice but to accept
your control of the system.
The queen has great faith
that the senate will side with her.
Queen Amidala
is young and naive.
You will find controlling her
will not be difficult.
Yes, my lord.
You didn't tell him
about the missing Jedi.
No need to report that to him
until we have something to report.
- Where wesa goin?
- Don't worry. The Force will guide us.
Ohh, maxi big, da Force.
Well, dat smells
stinkowiff.
-[Alarm Blaring]
- We're losing power.
[Whimpers]
Ohhh, no!
Wesa dyin' here.
[Sobbing]
- Just relax. We're not in trouble yet.
- What "yet"?
Monsters out dare.
Leak'n in here.
All sink'n and no power?
Whena yousa tinkin wesa in trouble?
- Power's back.
- Huh?
Aah, monster's back!
[Blubbering]
[Roars]
- [Whimpering]
- Relax.
- Ohh.
- You overdid it.
[Growling]
[Roaring]
- Horrible.
- Head for that outcropping.
[Blubbers]
Oh, boy.
Viceroy, we have
captured the queen.
Ah, victory.
[Birds Squawking]
Mmm, dis'n loverly.
[Engine Powering Down]
How will you explain
this invasion to the senate?
The queen and I will sign a treaty that
will legitimize our occupation here.
I have assurances
it will be ratified by the senate.
- I will not cooperate.
- Now, now, Your Highness.
I n time, the suffering of your people
will persuade you to see
our point of view.
- Commander.
- Yes, sir.
- Process them.
- Captain, take them to Camp 4.
Roger, roger.
Whoops!
[JarJar]
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- We should leave the street,
Your Highness.
- Get their weapons.
Whoa!
Yousa guys bombad!
We're ambassadors
for the supreme chancellor.
Your negotiations seemed
to have failed, Ambassador.
The negotiations
never took place.
It's urgent that we make contact
with the Republic.
- They've knocked out
all our communications.
- Do you have transports?
In the main hangar.
This way.
- There are too many of them.
- That won't be a problem.
Your Highness, under the circumstances,
I suggest you come to Coruscant with us.
Thank you, Ambassador,
but my place is with my people.
- They will kill you if you stay.
- They wouldn't dare.
They need her to sign a treaty
to make this invasion legal.
They can't afford to kill her.
There is something else behind all this,
Your Highness.
There's no logic
in the Federation's move here.
My feelings tell me
they will destroy you.
Our only hope is for
the senate to side with us.
Senator Palpatine
will need your help.
Either choice presents
great danger... to us all.
We are brave,
Your Highness.
If you are to leave,
Your Highness, it must be now.
Then I will plead our case
to the senate.
Be careful, Governor.
We'll need to free
those pilots.
I'll deal with that.
- Halt!
- I'm ambassador to
the supreme chancellor.
I'm taking these people
to Coruscant.
- Where are you taking them?
- To Coruscant.
Coruscant?
Uh, that doesn't compute.
Uh, wait.
You're under arrest.
Come on. Move!
Go!
Now, stay here
and keep out of trouble.
- Hello, boyos.
- [Beeping, Whistling]
There's the blockade.
- [Alarm Beeping]
- The shield generator's been hit!
[Alarm Blaring]
[Beeping]
[Gasps]
How wude!
[Whistling]
We're losing droids fast.
If we can't get the shield generator
fixed, we'll be sitting ducks.
- The shields are gone.
- [Whistling, Beeping]
The power's back!
[Beeping]
That little droid did it.
He bypassed the main power drive.
Deflector shields up
at maximum.
There's not enough power to get us
to Coruscant. The hyperdrive is leaking.
We'll have to land somewhere
to refuel and repair the ship.
Here, Master.
Tatooine.
Small, out of the way, poor. The Trade
Federation have no presence there.
How can you
be sure?
It's controlled
by the Hutts.
You can't take Her Royal Highness there.
The Hutts are gangsters.
- If they discovered her...
- It'd be no different
than if we landed...
on a system controlled
by the Federation,
except that the Hutts aren't looking
for her, which gives us the advantage.
And Queen Amidala,
has she signed the treaty?
She has disappeared,
my lord.
One Naboo cruiser
got past the blockade.
[Snarls]
I want that treaty signed.
My lord,
it's impossible
to locate the ship.
It's out of our range.
Not for a Sith.
This is my apprentice,
Darth Maul.
He will find
your lost ship.
This is getting
out of hand.
Now there are two of them.
We should not
have made this bargain.
An extremely well-put-together
little droid, Your Highness.
Without a doubt, it saved the ship,
as well as our lives.
It is to be commended.
What is its number?
[Chirping, Beeping]
R2-D2, Your Highness.
- Thank you, R2-D2.
- [Happy Chirping]
Padme.
Clean this droid up
as best you can.
It deserves our gratitude.
[Whistling]
Continue, Captain.
Your Highness,
with your permission,
we're heading for a remote planet
called Tatooine.
It's in a system far beyond the reach
of the Trade Federation.
I do not agree
with the Jedi on this.
You must trust my judgment,
Your Highness.
[Beeping]
[JarJar]
Hello.
Sorry.
Husa are yousa?
I'm Padme.
Mesa JarJar Binks.
You're a Gungan,
aren't you?
Uh-huh.
- How'd you end up here with us?
- My no know.
Mesa day starten pitty okeyday
witda brisky morning munchen.
Den boom!
Getten berry scared...
and grabben dat Jedi,
and pow... mesa here.
- [Chirps]
- Huh. Mesa getten berry, berry scared.
[Beeping]
- That's it... Tatooine.
- There's a settlement.
Land near the outskirts.
We don't want to attract attention.
The hyperdrive generator's gone, Master.
We'll need a new one.
That'll complicate things.
Be wary.
- I sense a disturbance in the Force.
- I feel it also, Master.
Don't let them send
any transmissions.
This sun doen murder
to mesa skin.
[Captain]
Wait!
Wait.
Her Highness commands you
to take her handmaiden with you.
No more commands from
Her Highness today, Captain.
The spaceport is not
going to be pleasant.
The queen wishes it.
She's curious
about the planet.
[Sighs]
This is not a good idea.
Stay close to me.
[Chirps, Beeping]
Moisture farms,
for the most part.
Some indigenous tribes
and scavengers.
The few spaceports like this one
are havens for those
that don't wish to be found.
Like us.
Dissen berry
berry bad.
- [Sloshing Sound]
- Oh! Icky icky goo!
[Chattering]
[Creature Snorts]
We'll try one
of the smaller dealers.
[Bell Dinging]
[Speaking Huttese]
Good day to you.
What do you want?
I need parts for a J-type 327 Nubian.
Ah, yes! Nubian.
We have lots of that.
Boy, get in here now!
- My droid has a readout of what I need.
- [Grunting]
[Speaking Huttese]
What took you so long?
I was cleaning the fan switches.
Watch the store.
I've got some selling to do.
So... let me take thee
out back, huh?
Ni you'll find what you need.
[Chuckling]
- Hmm?
- Don't touch anything.
Hmph!
Hmm.
- Are you an angel?
- What?
An angel. I heard the deep space
pilots talk about them.
They're the most beautiful
creatures in the universe.
They live on the moons
of lego, I think.
You're a funny little boy.
How do you know so much?
I listen to all the traders
and star pilots who come through here.
I'm a pilot, you know, and someday
I'm gonna fly away from this place.
- You're a pilot?
- Mm-hmm. All my life.
How long have you
been here?
Since I was very little.
Three, I think.
My mom and I were sold
to Gardulla the Hutt,
but she lost us betting
on the Podraces.
You're a slave?
- I'm a person, and my name is Anakin.
- I'm sorry.
I don't fully understand.
This is a strange place to me.
Hmm. Hmm.
Where... Wheres
yousa goin?
- Ugh!
- [Laughing]
[JarJar Grunting]
- [Blubbering] I got ya.
- Hey!
- What?
- Hit the nose.
Oh! Uh.
A T-1 4 hyperdrive generator.
Thee in luck.
I'm the only one
hereabouts who has one.
But thee might as well buy a new ship.
It would be cheaper, huh?
[Chuckles]
Saying of which,
how's thee gonna pay
for all this, huh?
I have 20,000
Republic dataries.
Republic credits?
Republic credits are no good out here.
I need something more real.
I don't have anything else,
but credits will do fine.
- No, they won't.
- Credits will do fine.
No, they won't!
What, you think you're some kind of
Jedi, waving your hand around like that?
I'm a Toydarian. Mind tricks
don't work on me. Only money.
- No money, no parts, no deal.
- [Beeping]
And no one else has a T-14 hyperdrive,
I promise you that.
[Grunts]
Wouldn't have lasted long anyways if
I wasn't so good at building things.
Oh! Aw! Ooh! Uh!
- Ai, ai! Whoa, ai!
- We're leaving. JarJar.
- Whaaa!
-[Metal Clanging, Crashing]
I'm glad to have
met you, Anakin.
I was glad to meet you too.
What? Wha... Oh.
[Groaning]
[Speaking In Huttese]
Outlanders. They think we know nothing.
They seemed nice to me.
Clean the racks.
Then you can go home.
Yippee!
[Sighs]
[Qui-Gon] And you're sure
there's nothing left on board?
A few containers of supplies.
The queen's wardrobe, maybe,
but not enough for you to barter with,
not in the amount
you're talking about.
All right. I'm sure another solution
will present itself.
I'll check back later.
Noah gain!
Noah gain.
Da beings hereabouts,
cawazy!
Wesa be wobbed
un crunched!
Not likely. We have nothing of value.
That's our problem.
[Whistling]
Hmm?
Ah, mooie-mooie.
Hey, hey! [Speaking Huttese]
Are you going to pay for that?
Huh? Wanga?
It costs seven wupiupi.
Ah! Chubaa...
Oops.
[Whistling]
[Growling]
[Speaking Huttese]
Is this yours?
Who, mesa? [Gags]
[Alien Speaking In Huttese]
Ouch! Ouch!
[Speaking Huttese]
Careful, Sebulba.
He's a big-time outlander.
I'd hate to see you diced
before we race again.
Next time we race, boy,
it will be the end of you.
If you weren't a slave,
I'd squash you now.
Yeah, it'd be a pity
if you had to pay for me.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
Your buddy here was about
to be turned into orange goo.
He picked a fight with a Dug, an
especially dangerous Dug called Sebulba.
Mesa haten crunchen.
Das da las ting mesa want.
Nevertheless, the boy is right.
You were heading into trouble.
Thanks, my young friend.
But... But...
- But mesa doen nutten!
- [Growls]
[Wind Whistling]
This storm
will slow them down.
- Looks pretty bad.
- [Beeps]
- Panaka.
- [Man] Receiving a message from home.
- We'll be right there.
- [Beeps]
[Anakin]
Here, you'll like these pallies.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Oh, my bones are aching.
Storm's coming up, Ani.
You better get home quick.
- Do you have shelter?
- We'll head back to our ship.
- Is it far?
- It's on the outskirts.
You'll never reach
the outskirts in time.
Sandstorms are very,
very dangerous.
Come on.
I'll take you to my place.
[Whistling, Beeping]
[Exhaling]
Mom!
- Mom, I'm home!
-[JarJar] Ahh, dissen cozy.
- These are my friends, Mom.
- [JarJar] Hello.
- I'm Qui-Gon J inn.
- I'm building a droid. You wanna see?
Your son was kind enough
to offer us shelter.
- Come on. I'll show you 3PO.
- Oh, mooie-mooie.
[Beeping, Chirping]
Isn't he great?
He's not finished yet.
He's wonderful.
- [Beeping]
-[Anakin] You really like him?
He's a protocol droid
to help Mom. Watch.
Oh. Oh. Uh...
Where is everybody?
Whoops. Yeah.
Oh, hello.
I am C-3 PO,
human-cyborg relations.
How might I serve you?
- He's perfect.
- Oh. Perfect.
When the storm is over, I'll show you
my racer. I'm building a Podracer.
- [Whistling]
- I'm not sure this floor
is entirely stable.
Oh, hello. I don't believe we
have been introduced.
[Excited Beeping]
R2-D2.
A pleasure to meet you.
I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
[Chirping, Bleeping]
I beg your pardon,
but what do you mean, " naked"?
My parts are showing?
My goodness! Oh!
The death toll
is catastrophic.
We must bow
to their wishes.
You must contact me.
It's a trick.
Send no reply.
Send no transmissions
of any kind.
It sounds like bait
to establish a connection trace.
What if it is true,
and the people are dying?
Either way,
we're running out of time.
Tatooine is
sparsely populated.
If the trace was correct,
I will find them quickly, Master.
Move against
the Jedi first.
You will then have no difficulty
in taking the queen to Naboo...
to sign the treaty.
At last we will reveal
ourselves to the Jedi.
At last we will
have revenge.
You have been well-trained,
my young apprentice.
They will be
no match for you.
All slaves have a transmitter
placed inside their bodies somewhere.
I've been working on a scanner
to try and locate mine.
- Any attempt to escape...
- And they blow you up!
- Boom!
- How wude!
I can't believe there's
still slavery in the galaxy.
The Republic's
antislavery laws...
The Republic
doesn't exist out here.
We must survive
on our own.
[Gulps]
Xcuse me.
Has anybody ever seen
a Podrace?
They have Podracing on Malastare.
Very fast, very dangerous.
I'm the only human
who can do it.
You must have Jedi reflexes
if you race pods.
- [Gasps]
- Don't do that again.
[Yelping, Blubbering]
You're a Jedi knight,
aren't you?
What makes you think that?
I saw your laser sword.
Only Jedis carry that kind of weapon.
Perhaps I killed a Jedi
and took it from him.
I don't think so.
No one can kill a Jedi.
I wish that were so.
I had a dream
I was a Jedi.
I came back here
and freed all the slaves.
- Have you come to free us?
- No, I'm afraid not.
I think you have.
Why else would you be here?
I can see there's
no fooling you, Anakin.
We're on our way to Coruscant,
the central system in the Republic,
on a very important mission.
How did you end up out here
in the outer rim?
Our ship was damaged, and we're stranded
here until we can repair it.
I can help.
- I can fix anything.
-[Qui-Gon] I believe you can.
But first we must acquire
the parts we need.
Wit no-nutten mula
to trade.
These junk dealers must have
a weakness of some kind.
Gambling. Everything here revolves
around betting on those awful races.
Podracing.
Greed can be a powerful ally.
I built a racer.
It's the fastest ever.
There's a big race tomorrow
on Boonta Eve.
- You could enter my pod.
-[Mother] Anakin!
- Watto won't let you.
- Watto doesn't know I've built it.
You could make him think
it was yours...
and get him to let me
pilot it for you.
I don't want you to race. It's awful.
I die every time Watto makes you do it.
But, Mom, I love it.
The prize money would more than pay
for the parts they need.
Anakin.
Your mother's right.
Is there anyone friendly to the Republic
who can help us?
No.
Mom, you say the biggest problem in this
universe is nobody helps each other.
I'm sure Qui-Gon doesn't want
to put your son in danger.
We'll find some other way.
No.
There is no other way.
I may not like it,
but he can help you.
He was meant
to help you.
[Growling]
Are you sure about this?
Trusting our fate
to a boy we hardly know?
The queen
will not approve.
doesn't need to know.
Well, I don't approve.
-[Bell Dings]
- The boy tells me you want to
sponsor him in the race.
How can you do this? Not on
the Republic credits, I think, huh?
My ship will be
the entry fee.
Oh, not bad!
Not bad, huh?
A Nubian, huh?
It's in good order,
except for the parts I need.
What would the boy ride?
He smashed up my pod in the last race.
It will take some long time to fix it.
It wasn't my fault, really.
Sebulba flashed me with his vents.
I actually saved the pod,
mostly.
Mmm. That you did, huh.
[Chuckling]
The boy's good.
No doubts there, huh?
I have acquired a pod in a game
of chance, the fastest ever built.
I hope you didn't kill
anyone I know for it, huh?
[Laughing]
So, you supply the pod
and the entry fee,
and I supply the boy.
We split the winnings,
um, 50-50, I think, huh?
If it's going to be 50-50, I suggest
you front the cash for the entry.
If we win,
you keep all the winnings,
minus the cost of the parts I need.
And if we lose,
you keep my ship.
Either way, you win.
[Grumbling]
[Grumbling Continues]
Deal!
[Speaking Huttese]
Your friend is a foolish one, methinks.
What if this plan fails,
Master?
We could be stuck here
a very long time.
Well, it's too dangerous
to call for help,
and a ship without a power supply
isn't going to get us anywhere.
And...
there's something
about this boy.
You should be very proud
of your son.
He gives without
any thought of reward.
Well, he knows
nothing of greed.
- He has a...
- He has special powers.
Yes.
He can see things
before they happen.
That's why he appears
to have such quick reflexes.
It's a Jedi trait.
-He deserves better than a slave's life.
- Why, certainly.
Had he been born in the Republic,
we would have identified him early.
The Force is unusually strong with him.
That much is clear.
Who was his father?
There was no father.
I carried him, I gave birth,
I raised him.
I can't explain
what happened.
Can you help him?
I don't know.
I didn't actually
come here to free slaves.
[Giggling]
Hey, hi, Ani.
Hi.
-[R2-D 2 Beeping]
- Wow, a real astro droid.
[Beeping]
- How did you get so lucky?
- That isn't the half of it.
- I'm in the Boonta race tomorrow.
- What?
With this?
[Speaking Alien Language]
You're such a joker, Ani.
- You've been working on
that thing for years.
- It's never gonna run.
Come on.
Let's go and play ball.
Keep racing, Ani.
You're gonna be bug squash.
[All Giggling]
Hey, JarJar.
- [Gasps]
- Keep away from those energy binders.
If your hand gets caught in the beam,
it's gonna go numb for hours.
Sorry. Okay.
[Yelping, Blubbering]
[Muffled]
My tongue is fat.
My tongue...
Wrench.
Where is da wrench?
Oh, dare it is.
Hey. Uh-oh.
Uh, Ani, I'm stuck.
Ani...
You know, I find that JarJar creature
to be a little odd.
[Gurgling]
You don't even know
if this thing's gonna run.
- It will.
- I think it's time we found out.
- Here, use this power charge.
- Yes, sir!
Come on, Kitster.
Let's move away.
[Muffled]
My... My mouth.
Ani, I'm stuck.
[Babbling]
Uh, hey.
My tongue is fat. Ani!
You're quite right.
He's very odd indeed.
Oh. Th... Thank you.
Go.
[Engine Humming]
It's working!
Stay still, Ani.
Let me clean this cut.
There's so many.
Do they all have a system of planets?
Most of them.
Has anyone been
to 'em all?
[Chuckles]
Not likely.
I wanna be the first one
to see 'em all.
-[Mother] Ani, bedtime!
- Ow!
There we are.
Good as new.
Ani, I'm not gonna
tell you again.
- What are you doing?
- Checking your blood for infections.
Go on. You have
a big day tomorrow.
Sleep well, Ani.
- Obi-Wan?
- Yes, Master?
I need an analysis of this blood sample
I'm sending you.
- Wait a minute.
- [Beeping]
I need
a midi-chlorian count.
The reading
is off the chart.
Over 20,000.
Even Master Yoda doesn't have
a midi-chlorian count that high.
No Jedi has.
What does that mean?
I'm not sure.
[Rhythmic Tones Sounding,
Whirring]
- [Jabbering]
-[Creature Trumpeting]
I wanna see your spaceship
the moment the race is over.
Patience, my blue friend. You'll have
your winnings before the suns set.
And we'll be far away
from here.
Not if your ship belongs
to me, I think, huh?
[Laughs]
I warn you, no funny business.
- You don't think Anakin can win?
- Don't get me wrong, no.
I have great faith
in the boy.
He's a credit
to your race,
but, uh, Sebulba there
is going to win, I think.
[Laughing]
Oh, no!
[Speaking Huttese]
Why do you think that?
He always wins!
[Laughing]
I am betting heavily
on Sebulba.
- I'll take that bet.
- You what?
I'll wager my new racing pod
against, say,
the boy and his mother.
No pod is worth two slaves,
not by a long shot.
The boy, then.
Hmm. Well, uh...
We'll let fate decide,
huh?
I just happen to have
a chance cube here.
Blue, it's the boy.
Red, uh... his mother.
[Grumbling]
You won this small toss, outlander,
but you won't win the race!
So it makes
little difference!
[Creature Groaning]
[Watto Speaking Huttese]
Better stop your friend's betting,
or I'll end up owning him too.
[Chuckling]
- What'd he mean by that?
- I'll tell you later.
Good morning.
-[Bleeping]
- Oh, my.
Space travel sounds
rather perilous.
[Beeping]
I can assure you, they will never get
me onto one of those dreadful starships.
This is so wizard, Ani.
I'm sure you'll do it this time.
- Do what?
- Finish the race, of course.
- You've never won a race?
- Well, not exactly.
Not even finished?
Kitster's right.
I will this time.
Of course you will.
[Whirring]
[Crowd Cheering]
[Announcer Speaking
In Huttese]
[Continues]
...Podracers.
That's absolutely right.
And a big turnout here from all corners
of the outer rim territories.
I see the contestants are making
their way out onto the starting grid.
[Announcer
Speaking In Huttese]
from the Tund System.
[Announcer
Two-time winner Boles Roor.
[Speaking Huttese]
Sebulba!
[Crowd Cheering]
[Speaking I n Huttese]
And in the front row,
nearside pole position,
Mawhonic!
- [Shouts]
-A hearty hello...
to Clegg Holdfast
and his Voltec KT9 Wasp!
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
And back again,
it's the mighty Dud Bolt...
with that incredible racing machine,
the Vulptereen 3 2 7.
-And hoping for a big win today,
- [Jabbering]
Ody Mandrell, with his
record-setting pit droid team.
[Bleeping]
[Tool Whirring]
And a late entry,
young Anakin Skywalker,
- A local boy.
- [Cheering]
I see the flags are moving
out onto the track.
-[Flatulence]
- Huh? [Sniffs]
[Snorting]
[Blubbering]
Pee yousa!
Be safe.
I will, Mom.
I promise.
Uh-oh.
[Snickering]
[Speaking I n Huttese]
You won't walk away from this one,
you slave scum.
Don't count on it, slime ball.
You're bantha fodder!
[Chuckling, Muttering]
- You all set, Ani?
- Yep.
- Right.
- Whoa!
Remember, concentrate
on the moment.
Feel, don't think.
Use your instincts.
I will.
May the Force
be with you.
[Fanfare]
[Speaking I n Huttese]
Jabba the Hutt.
[Ululating]
[Spectators Cheering]
Mmm.
[Muttering I n Huttese]
[Speaking Huttese]
Welcome.
Begin the race!
[Announcer
Speaking In Huttese]
they're clearing the grid.
- Is he nervous?
- He's fine.
You Jedi are far too reckless.
The queen is not...
The queen trusts my judgment,
young handmaiden.
You should too.
You assume too much.
[Announcer
Start your engines.
Oh, dissen gonna be messy.
Me no watch'n!
Oh!
[Squeaks]
- [Clang]
- [Beep]
Oh, no! No!
[Engine Clicking,
Winding Down]
[Chuckles]
Wait. Little Skywalker has stalled.
- [Cursing I n Alien Language]
- [All Laughing]
[Announcer
Well, it looks like Quadinaros
is having engine trouble also.
- Come on, Ani!
- [Engine Clicking, Whirring]
-[Announcer
-And there goes Skywalker!
- Go, Ani, go!
He will be hard-pressed
to catch up with the leaders.
- Ehh!
- [Cursing I n Huttese]
Haaaa!
[Speaking I n Tusken Dialect]
Looks like a few Tusken Raiders
are camped out on the canyon dune turn.
[Shouting]
Doowat macroon!
Ooh, there goes
Quadinaros' power coupling.
Cheespa will be!
Ooh!
-[Announcer
Chubba ni chees Sebulba!
- Packet!
Kulkah doka!
- [Beep]
-[Announcer
Ody Mandrell coona of wound!
[Fussing I n Alien Language]
[Squeaking]
Whoa!
[Laughing]
Oh, no!
- Oh.
- [Screaming]
- Where is Master Anakin?
- [Beeping]
Look.
Here he comes.
[Announcer
is moving up in the field.
Yay!
Yippee!
[Talking I n Alien Language]
- [Beeping]
- He has to complete two more circuits?
Oh, dear.
Ah.
[Grunts]
He has!
Arrr!
Skywalker's spinning
out of control!
[Gasps]
Oh, I don't care what universe
you're from. That's gotta hurt!
Here he comes!
Money!
[Announcer
the final lap, Sebulba's in the lead,
followed closely by Skywalker!
Go, Ani!
-[Spectators Gasping]
- Skywalker's been forced
onto the service ramp!
[Engine Winding Down]
Whoa-oa!
- Huh?
- [Engine Starts]
- It's Skywalker!
- Sebulba!
Amazing! A quick control thrust,
and he's back on course!
Did he crash-ed?
- [Chattering]
- Wah hota!
[Beeping]
[Laughing]
Skywalker's in trouble!
Sebulba takes the lead!
[Spectators Continue Cheering]
- He's catching Sebulba!
- Inkabunga!
Careful, Ani.
Careful, Ani!
Wha...
Chuba da noya!
[Spectators Cheering]
- That little human being
is out of his mind.
- Punda tah punda!
- They're side by side!
- Bangu du bangu!
Wa-waaaaah!
Aaah!
Poo doo!
[Cheering]
- Yippee!
- Yay!
Ya eeka buta!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- [Beeping]
- I can't believe it.
The crowds
are going nuts!
Oh! Ah!
[Chanting]
Ooh! Ah! Ooh! Ah! Ooh! Ah! Ooh! Ah!
[JarJar]
Yay, Ani!
Mom, I did it!
Yeah!
[Arguing]
[Snoring]
[Muttering, Speaking Huttese]
Ohh!
[JarJar]
Good going, Ani!
[Chanting Continues, Faint]
We owe you everything,
Ani.
- Mmm!
- Aww.
It's so wonderful,
Ani.
You have brought hope
to those who have none.
I'm so very proud
of you.
[Creature Bellows]
Aww.
Oy chuba no.
[Sighs]
You.
You swindled me!
You knew the boy was going to win.
Somehow you knew it.
I lost everything.
Whenever you gamble, my friend,
eventually you'll lose.
Bring the parts
to the main hangar.
I'll come by your shop later on
so you can release the boy.
You can't have him.
It wasn't a fair bet.
- Would you like to discuss
it with the Hutts?
-[Grumbles]
I'm sure
they can settle this.
Take him.
[JarJar]
Hidoe!
Well, we have all
the essential parts we need.
I'm going back. Some unfinished
business. I won't be long.
Why do I sense we've picked up
another pathetic life-form?
It's the boy who's responsible
for getting us these parts.
Get this hyperdrive
generator installed.
Yes, Master.
That shouldn't take long.
- Come on. Hup!
-[Creature Grunts]
Hey.
These are yours.
Yes!
Mom, we sold the pod!
- Look at all the money we have!
- My goodness!
- But that's so wonderful, Ani.
-And he has been freed.
- What?
- You're no longer a slave.
Did you hear that?
Now you can make
your dreams come true, Ani.
You are free.
Will you take him
with you?
- Is he to become a Jedi?
- Yes.
Our meeting
was not a coincidence.
Nothing happens
by accident.
You mean I get to come with you
in your starship?
Anakin,
training to become a Jedi
is not an easy challenge,
and even if you succeed,
it's a hard life.
But I wanna go.
It's what I've always dreamed of doing.
Can I go, Mom?
Anakin,
this path has been placed
before you.
The choice
is yours alone.
I wanna do it.
Then pack your things.
We haven't much time.
Yippee!
What about Mom?
Is she free too?
I tried to free your mother, Ani,
but Watto wouldn't have it.
You're coming with us,
aren't you, Mom?
Son, my place is here.
My future is here.
It is time
for you to let go.
I don't want things
to change.
But you can't stop
the change...
any more than you can
stop the suns from setting.
Oh, I love you.
[Sighs]
Now hurry.
Thank you.
I'll watch after him.
You have my word.
Will you be all right?
Yeah.
Oh!
Oh, my. Oh!
Hello, Master Anakin.
Well, 3 PO,
I've been freed...
and I'm going away
in a starship.
Master Anakin, you are my maker
and I wish you well.
However, I should prefer it if
I were a little more completed.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to finish you,
3 PO, give you coverings and all.
I'm gonna miss working on you.
You've been a great pal.
I'll make sure Mom doesn't
sell you or anything.
Sell me?
Bye.
Oh, my.
I can't do it, Mom.
I just can't do it.
Ani.
Will I ever
see you again?
What does your heart
tell you?
I hope so.
Yes.
I guess.
Then we will
see each other again.
I will come back
and free you, Mom.
I promise.
Now, be brave...
and don't look back.
Don't look back.
[Probe Speaks
I n Droid Language]
- Qui-Gon, sir, wait! I'm tired!
- Anakin! Drop!
Go!
Tell them to take off!
Qui-Gon's
in trouble.
Take off.
Over there.
Fly low.
Are you all right?
I think so.
What was it?
I'm not sure, but it was
well-trained in the Jedi arts.
- [Beeps]
- My guess is it was after the queen.
What are we gonna do
about it?
[Sighs]
We shall be patient.
Anakin Skywalker,
meet Obi-Wan Kenobi.
- Hi.
-[R2-D 2 Beeping]
You're a Jedi too?
Pleased to meet you.
Your queen is lost,
your people are starving,
and you, Governor,
are going to die...
much sooner than your people,
I'm afraid.
This invasion
will gain you nothing.
We're a democracy.
The people have decided.
Take him away.
My troops are in position
to begin searching the swamps...
for these rumored
underwater villages.
They will not
stay hidden for long.
[Muttering, Snoring]
The death toll
is catastrophic.
We must bow
to their wishes.
You must
contact me.
You all right?
It's very cold.
[Continues Muttering, Snoring]
You come from
a warm planet, Ani.
A little too warm
for my taste.
Space is cold.
You seem sad.
The queen is worried.
Her people are suffering,
dying.
She must convince the senate
to intervene, or...
I'm not sure what'll happen.
I made this for you...
so you'd remember me.
I carved it
out of a japor snippet.
It'll bring you
good fortune.
It's beautiful.
But I don't need this
to remember you by.
Many things will change
when we reach the capital, Ani,
but my caring for you
will remain.
I care for you, too,
only l...
Miss your mother.
Coruscant.
The entire planet is one big city.
There's Chancellor Valorum's shuttle.
And look over there.
Senator Palpatine is waiting for us.
It is a great gift to see you alive,
Your Majesty.
With the communications breakdown,
we've been very concerned.
I'm anxious to hear your report
on the situation.
May I present
Supreme Chancellor Valorum.
Welcome, Your Highness. It's an honor
to finally meet you in person.
Thank you,
Supreme Chancellor.
I must relay to you how distressed
everyone is over the current situation.
I've called for a special session
of the senate to hear your position.
I'm grateful for your concern,
Chancellor.
There is a question
of procedure,
but I'm confident
we can overcome it.
I must speak with
the Jedi Council immediately.
The situation has become
much more complicated.
Ani, come on.
The queen's a bein' grossly nice,
mesa tinks.
Pitty hot.
[Men Conversing, Faint]
[Palpatine]
There is no civility, only politics.
The Republic
is not what it once was.
The senate is full of greedy,
squabbling delegates.
There is no interest...
in the common good.
I must be frank,
Your Majesty.
There is little chance the senate
will act on the invasion.
Chancellor Valorum
seems to think there is hope.
If I may say so, Your Majesty,
the chancellor has little real power.
He is mired by baseless
accusations of corruption.
- The bureaucrats are in charge now.
- What options have we?
Our best choice would be
to push for the election...
of a stronger
supreme chancellor,
one who could control
the bureaucrats...
and give us justice.
You could call for
a vote of no confidence...
in Chancellor Valorum.
He has been
our strongest supporter.
Our only other choice would be
to submit a plea to the courts.
The courts take even longer
to decide things than the senate.
Our people are dying,
Senator.
We must do something quickly
to stop the Federation.
To be realistic,
Your Majesty,
I think we're going to have to accept
Federation control for the time being.
That is something
I cannot do.
He was trained
in the Jedi arts.
My only conclusion can be
that it was a Sith lord.
I mpossible. The Sith have been
extinct for a millennium.
I do not believe the Sith
could have returned without us knowing.
Ah, hard to see,
the dark side is.
We will use all our resources
to unravel this mystery.
We will discover the identity
of your attacker.
May the Force
be with you.
[Yoda]
Master Qui-Gon.
More to say have you?
With your permission,
my master,
I have encountered
a vergence in the Force.
A vergence, you say?
Located around a person?
A boy.
His cells have the highest
concentration of midi-chlorians
I have seen in a life-form.
It is possible he was conceived
by the midi-chlorians.
You refer
to the prophecy...
of the one who will bring
balance to the Force.
You believe
it's this boy?
- I don't presume to...
-[Yoda] But you do.
Revealed your opinion is.
I request the boy
be tested, Master.
Oh? Trained as a Jedi
you request for him, hmm?
Finding him
was the will of the Force.
I have no doubt of that.
[Sighs]
Bring him before us, then.
- [Beeps]
- The boy's here to see Padme.
[Woman]
Let him in.
I'm sorry, Ani,
but Padme's not here right now.
Who is it?
Anakin Skywalker to see Padme,
Your Highness.
I've sent Padme
on an errand.
I'm on my way to the Jedi temple
to start my training, I hope.
I may never see her again,
so I came to say good-bye.
We will tell her for you.
We are sure
her heart goes with you.
Thank you, Your Highness.
The chair recognizes the senator
from the sovereign system of Naboo.
[Senators Murmuring]
[Palpatine] Supreme Chancellor,
delegates of the senate,
a tragedy has occurred...
which started right here
with the taxation of trade routes...
and has now engulfed
our entire planet...
in the oppression
of the Trade Federation.
This is outrageous!
I object to
the senator's statements.
The chair does not recognize the senator
from the Trade Federation at this time.
To state our allegations,
I present Queen Amidala,
recently elected
ruler of the Naboo,
who speaks
on our behalf.
[Murmuring Continues]
Honorable representatives
of the Republic,
I come to you under
the gravest of circumstances.
The Naboo system has been invaded
by the droid armies of the Trade...
I object!
There is no proof!
This is incredible.
We recommend a commission be sent
to Naboo to ascertain the truth.
The Congress of Malastare concurs...
with the honorable delegate
from the Trade Federation.
- A commission must be appointed.
- The point...
- Excuse me, Chancellor.
-[Palpatine] Enter the bureaucrat.
The true rulers
of the Republic.
And on the payroll of
the Trade Federation, I might add.
This is where Chancellor Valorum's
strength will disappear.
[Valorum]
The point is conceded.
Will you defer your motion
to allow a commission...
to explore the validity
of your accusations?
I will not defer.
I've come before you to resolve
this attack on our sovereignty now.
I was not elected to watch
my people suffer and die...
while you discuss this invasion
in a committee.
If this body
is not capable of action,
I suggest new leadership
is needed.
I move for a vote
of no confidence...
in Chancellor Valorum's
leadership.
[Senators Murmuring,
Shouting]
Vote now!
- [Chanting Continues]
Vote now! Vote now!
- Order!
Now they will elect
a new chancellor,
a strong chancellor,
one who will not let
our tragedy continue.
The boy will not pass the council's
test, Master. He's too old.
Anakin will become a Jedi,
I promise you.
Do not defy the council,
Master, not again.
I shall do what I must,
Obi-Wan.
If you would just follow the code,
you would be on the council.
They will not go along
with you this time.
You still have much to learn,
my young apprentice.
A ship.
A cup.
A speeder.
Hmm.
How feel you?
Cold, sir.
Afraid are you?
No, sir.
See through you we can.
Be mindful
of your feelings.
Your thoughts dwell
on your mother.
- I miss her.
-[Yoda] Mmm.
Afraid to lose her,
I think, mmm?
What has that got to do
with anything?
Everything.
Fear is the path
to the dark side.
Fear leads to anger.
Anger leads to hate.
Hate leads to suffering.
I sense much fear in you.
Yousa tinking
yousa people ganna die?
I don't know.
Gungans get pasted too, eh?
I hope not.
Gungans no dyin'
without a fight.
Wesa warriors.
Wesa got a grand army.
Dat's why you no liken us,
mesa tinks.
Your Highness?
Your Highness.
Senator Palpatine has been nominated
to succeed Valorum...
as supreme chancellor.
A surprise, to be sure,
but a welcome one.
Your Majesty, if I am elected,
I promise to put an end to corruption.
Who else
has been nominated?
Bail Antilles of Alderaan
and Ainlee Teem of Malastare.
I feel confident our situation will
create a strong sympathy vote for us.
I will be chancellor.
I fear by the time you have
control of the bureaucrats,
there'll be nothing left of our people,
our way of life.
I understand your concern,
Your Majesty.
Unfortunately, the Federation
has possession of our planet.
Senator,
this is your arena.
I feel I must
return to mine.
I've decided
to go back to Naboo.
Go back?
But, Your Majesty, be realistic.
They'll force you
to sign the treaty.
I will sign no treaty,
Senator.
My fate will be no different
than that of our people.
- Captain.
- Your Highness.
Ready my ship.
Please, Your Majesty,
stay here where it's safe.
It is clear to me now that
the Republic no longer functions.
I pray you will bring sanity
and compassion back to the senate.
The Force
is strong with him.
He is to be trained,
then?
No, he will not
be trained.
No?
He is too old.
He is the chosen one.
You must see it.
Mmm. Clouded
this boy's future is.
I will train him, then.
I take Anakin
as my Padawan learner.
An apprentice you have,
Qui-Gon.
I mpossible
to take on a second.
The code forbids it.
- Obi-Wan is ready.
- I am ready to face the trials.
Our own counsel we will keep
on who is ready.
He is headstrong,
and he has much to learn of
the living Force, but he is capable.
There is little more
he can learn from me.
Young Skywalker's fate...
will be decided later.
Now is not the time
for this.
The senate is voting
for a new supreme chancellor,
and Queen Amidala
is returning home,
which will put pressure
on the Federation and could
widen the confrontation.
And draw out
the queen's attacker.
Go with the queen to Naboo and discover
the identity of this dark warrior.
This is the clue we need...
to unravel
the mystery of the Sith.
May the Force
be with you.
It's not disrespect, Master.
It's the truth.
From your point of view.
The boy is dangerous.
They all sense it. Why can't you?
His fate is uncertain.
He's not dangerous.
The council will decide
Anakin's future.
That should be enough for you.
Now get on board.
[Whimpers]
Qui-Gon, sir,
I don't want to be a problem.
You won't be, Ani.
I'm not allowed to train you, so I want
you to watch me and be mindful.
Always remember:
Your focus
determines your reality.
Stay close to me
and you'll be safe.
Master, sir,
I heard Yoda talking
about midi-chlorians.
I've been wondering...
What are midi-chlorians?
Midi-chlorians are
a microscopic life-form...
that resides
within all living cells.
- They live inside me?
- I nside your cells, yes.
- And we are symbionts with them.
- Symbionts?
Life-forms living together
for mutual advantage.
Without the midi-chlorians,
life could not exist...
and we would have no
knowledge of the Force.
They continually
speak to us,
telling us
the will of the Force.
When you learn
to quiet your mind,
you'll hear them
speaking to you.
I don't understand.
With time and training, Ani,
you will. You will.
Your Majesty, it is our pleasure
to continue to serve and protect you.
I welcome your help.
Senator Palpatine fears that
the Federation means to destroy me.
I assure you I will not
allow that to happen.
Wesa goin' ho-o-o-me!
- Come on, R2.
- [Whistles]
Is the planet secure?
We have taken over the last pockets
of primitive life-forms.
We are in complete control
of the planet now.
Good. I will see to it that in
the senate things stay as they are.
I am sending my apprentice,
Darth Maul, to join you.
Yes, my lord.
A Sith here?
Those are
the forward stabilizers.
And those two
control the pitch?
You catch on
pretty quick.
[Panaka]
As soon as we land,
the Federation will arrest you
and force you to sign the treaty.
I agree. I'm not sure what
you wish to accomplish by this.
I will take back
what's ours.
There are too few of us,
Your Highness.
We have no army.
And I can only protect you.
I can't fight a war for you.
JarJar Binks.
Mesa, Your Highness?
Yes.
I need your help.
I have one battleship
on my scope.
[Obi-Wan]
It's a droid control ship.
They've probably
spotted us.
We haven't much time.
- JarJar is on his way
to the Gungan city, Master.
- Good.
Do you think the queen's idea
will work?
The Gungans will not
be easily swayed.
And we cannot use our power
to help her.
I'm... I'm sorry for
my behavior, Master.
It's not my place to disagree
with you about the boy.
And I am grateful you think
I'm ready to take the trials.
You've been a good apprentice,
Obi-Wan.
And you're a much wiser man
than I am.
I foresee you will become
a great Jedi knight.
[Grunts]
[Blubbering]
Desa nobody dare.
The Gungan city
is deserted.
Some kinda fight,
mesa tinks.
Do you think they have been
taken to the camps?
More likely
they were wiped out.
- Mesa no tink so.
- Do you know where they are, JarJar?
When in trouble,
Gungans go to sacred place.
Mesa show you.
Come on. Mesa show you!
[Creatures Bleating]
Your Honor,
Queen Amidala of the Naboo.
Uh, h-heyo dadee,
Big Boss Nass, Your Honor.
JarJar Binks.
Who's da uss-en uthers?
I am Queen Amidala
of the Naboo.
I come before you
in peace.
Ah, Naboo biggen.
Yousa bringen
da Mackineeks.
Yousa all bombad.
We have searched you out because
we wish to form an alliance.
Your Honor.
Whosa dis?
- I am Queen Amidala.
- Huh?
This is my decoy,
my protection,
my loyal bodyguard.
I'm sorry for my deception,
but it was necessary to protect myself.
Although we do not
always agree, Your Honor,
our two great societies
have always lived in peace.
- Ah.
- The Trade Federation...
has destroyed all that we
have worked so hard to build.
If we do not act quickly,
all will be lost forever.
I ask you to help us.
No, I beg you to help us.
We are
your humble servants.
Our fate
is in your hands.
Mmm.
[Whimpers]
[Boss Nass Sighs]
Ha!
[Laughing]
Yousa no tinken yousa
greater den da Gungans?
[Chuckling]
Me-e-esa lika dis!
Maybe...
wesa...
bein friends.
[Blubbering]
[All Cheering, Shouting]
Yippee!
Ya-hoo!
We've sent
our patrols.
We already located
their starship in the swamp.
It won't be long,
my lord.
This is an unexpected move
for her.
It's too aggressive.
Lord Maul, be mindful.
Let them
make the first move.
Yes, my master.
Deysa comin!
All right!
They're here!
Good.
They made it.
Yousa doen grand.
- [Chuckles]
- JarJar bring uss-en
and da Naboo together.
Ah, no, no, no.
So, wesa make you...
bombad general.
General?
[Moaning]
- [Qui-Gon] Captain.
- [Laughing]
- Your Highness.
- What is the situation?
Almost everyone's
in camps.
A few hundred police and guards
have formed an underground
resistance movement.
I brought back as many
of the leaders as I could.
The Federation army's also much larger
than we thought, and much stronger.
Your Highness, this is a battle
I do not think that we can win.
The battle
is a diversion.
The Gungans must draw the droid army
away from the cities.
- R2.
- [Beeps]
We can enter the city using the secret
passages on the waterfall side.
Once we get to
the main entrance,
Captain Panaka
will create a diversion.
Then we can enter the palace
and capture the viceroy.
Without the viceroy,
they will be lost and confused.
What do you think,
MasterJedi?
The viceroy will be
well-guarded.
The difficulty is getting
into the throne room.
Once we're inside,
we shouldn't have a problem.
There is a possibility, with this
diversion, many Gungans will be killed.
Wesa ready to do
our-san part.
[Amidala] We have a plan which
should immobilize the droid army.
We will send
what pilots we have...
to knock out the droid control ship
orbiting the planet.
A well-conceived plan.
However, there's great risk.
The weapons on your fighters
may not penetrate the shields.
[Obi-Wan]
There's an even bigger danger.
If the viceroy escapes,
Your Highness,
he will return
with another droid army.
Well, that is why we must not
fail to get the viceroy.
Everything depends on it.
[Beeps, Whistles]
She is more foolish
than I thought.
We are sending all troops to meet
this army assembling near the swamp.
It appears to be made up
of primitives.
This will work
to our advantage.
I have your approval
to proceed, then, my lord?
Wipe them out.
All of them.
[Bellowing]
Halt!
Starting up the shield.
[Rumbling]
[Loud Whirring]
Open fire.
Once we get inside, you find
a safe place to hide and stay there.
- Sure.
- Stay there.
[Droids Squawking]
Roger. Roger.
I thought the battle was going
to take place far from here.
This is too close.
Ani, find cover.
- Quick!
- Get to your ships!
Aah!
[Whistling, Beeping]
[Continues Beeping]
[Beeps]
- Fighters straight ahead.
- Roger, Bravo Leader.
Roger, Bravo Leader.
Cease fire.
[Murmuring]
Steady. Steady.
- Activate the droids.
- Yes, sir.
Ouch time.
Fire!
Whoa-ohh!
Aah! Whoa!
My guess is the viceroy's
in the throne room.
Red group! Blue group!
Everybody, this way!
Hey, wait for me!
Stay where you are.
You'll be safe there.
- But l...
- Stay in that cockpit.
- We'll handle this.
- We'll take the long way.
[Beeps]
We gotta do something, R2.
[Continues Beeping]
I'm trying to!
I don't know where the trigger is!
Oops, wrong one.
Maybe it's this one.
Nope. Wait.
Here it is.
Yeah!
Let's go!
It's on automatic pilot.
- Try to override it.
-[R2-D 2 Beeping]
We don't have time
for this, Captain.
[Beeping]
Look! There they are.
That's where
the autopilot's taking us.
Huh? Waaah!
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Aaah! Hmm!
Dumb droid. Take that!
Get off! Get off!
Ooh! Ooh! Mooie!
Whoo-hoo! Aah!
The deflector shield
is too strong.
- [Whistles]
- This is tense!
Whoa! R2, get us
off this autopilot.
It's gonna
get us both killed.
- [Continues Beeping]
- You did it, R2!
Okay, let's go left.
- [Continues Beeping]
- Go back?
Qui-Gon told me to stay in this cockpit,
so that's what I'm gonna do.
I'll try spinning.
That's a good trick.
Whoa!
- [Whistles]
- I know we're in trouble. J ust hang on.
Go!
Ascension guns!
[Force Field
Humming, Buzzing]
[Whistles]
Retreat! Retreat!
Dis is nutsen.
Hyah!
O-O-Ohh!
Uh-oh.
Big boomers.
Ohh! Ohh!
[Gasps]
Uh-oh! Aaah!
[Whimpering]
Hey! Hey!
Give me a lift!
Aaah! Oh!
Aaah!
Ohh!
JarJar, usen da booma!
What?
Mesa no have a booma!
Here. Taken dis one.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Whoa-ohh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Aaah!
Help me!
JarJar!
J ump, JarJar, jump!
[Blubbering]
Put down your weapons.
They win this round.
[Shrieks]
We're hit, R2!
Aah!
[Whistling]
Aaah!
[Beeping]
I'm trying to stop!
[Beeps]
Everything's overheated.
-[R2-D 2 Beeps]
- Oops. This is not good.
No!
No giben up,
General JarJar.
Mesa tink
of something.
- Hands up.
- My give up.
- [Groans]
Your little insurrection
is at an end, Your Highness.
Time for you to sign the treaty and end
this pointless debate in the senate.
Viceroy!
Your occupation here
has ended.
After her.
This one's a decoy.
Captain!
Jam the doors.
Now, Viceroy,
we will discuss a new treaty.
[Groans]
-[R2-D 2 Beeps]
- Yes! We have power.
Shields up.
Take this!
And this!
Whoa!
- Oops.
- We're losing power.
- There seems to be a problem
with the main reactor.
- Impossible!
Nothing can get
through our shield.
- Let's get outta here.
- [Beeping]
What's that?
It's blowing up from the inside!
We didn't hit it.
- Now, this is Podracing.
- [Whistles]
- Look, one of ours,
out of the main hold!
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
- Hee-hee!
- [Motors Winding Down]
- What the...
Was'n they doing?
The control ship has
been destroyed. Look!
They all broke-ed.
[All Hooting, Cheering]
[Grunts]
[Groans]
[Muttering]
No, it... it's too late.
- No.
- Obi-Wan.
Promise...
Promise me
you will train the boy.
Yes, Master.
He is the chosen one.
He... will bring balance.
Train him.
Now, Viceroy,
you're going to have to go back
to the senate and explain all this.
I think you can kiss your
trade franchise good-bye.
We are indebted to you for
your bravery, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
And you,
young Skywalker.
We will watch your career
with great interest.
Congratulations on your election,
Chancellor.
Your boldness has saved
our people, Your Majesty.
It's you who should be
congratulated.
Together we shall bring peace
and prosperity to the Republic.
Confer on you the level of
Jedi knight the council does.
But agree with your taking this boy
as your Padawan learner...
I do not.
Qui-Gon believed in him.
[Sighs]
The chosen one
the boy may be.
Nevertheless,
grave danger I fear
in his training.
Master Yoda,
I gave Qui-Gon my word.
I will train Anakin.
Ohh!
[Grunting]
Without the approval of the council,
if I must.
Qui-Gon's defiance
I sense in you.
Need that you do not.
Agree with you
the council does.
Your apprentice
Skywalker will be.
[Sighs]
[Whimpers, Beeps]
What will happen to me now?
The council have granted me
permission to train you.
You will be a Jedi,
I promise.
There's no doubt
the mysterious warrior was a Sith.
Mmm.
Always two there are.
No more, no less.
A master
and an apprentice.
But which
was destroyed?
The master
or the apprentice?
[Crowd Cheering]
Hello, everybody!
[Chuckling]
[Continues]
- [Growls]
-[Children Laughing]
Peace!
- Ya-hoo!
- [Cheering Continues]
[Beeping]
- [Growls]
-[Children Laughing]
[Beeping]